Guide to the Montana Department of Environmental Quality, Director's Office records 1908-2002
Montana Historical Society
Montana Department of Environmental Quality, Director's Office records
1908-2002
Montana Historical Society Archives
RS 433
Montana. Department of Environmental Quality.
90 linear feet of shelf space
This collection is comprised of records documenting the work of the Director’s Office of the Department of Environmental Quality, including correspondence, hearings, and subject files.
The Montana State Board of Health was established in 1901. In 1967 the Legislative Assembly created the State Department of Health. The State Board of Health continued in an advisory capacity, but the day-to-day administration of the state laws regarded public health and related matters were relegated to the new department. The State Board of Health became The Department of Health and Environmental Sciences in 1971 with the passage of Governor Anderson’s Executive Reorganization Order 9-71. In 1991, though it remained a part of the Department of Health and Environmental Sciences, the role of the Environmental Sciences Division was considerably expanded to include: Natural Resource Damage Assessment, a Petroleum Tank Release Compensation Board, a Superfund Section, and an Underground Storage Tanks Section.
The Environmental Sciences Division eventually became its own separate department, renamed the Department of Environmental Quality, in 1995, comprised of the following divisions: Director’s Office, Air Quality, Centralized Services, Energy, Environmental Remediation, Reclamation, Waste Management, and Water Quality.
The public health-related functions of DHES meanwhile fell under the umbrella of a new agency, The Department of Public Health and Human Services (DPHHS), which, at the time of its creation, was comprised of the following divisions: Child and Family Services, Child Support Enforcement, Disability Services, Health Policy and Services, Mental and Addictive Disorders, Operations and Technology, Quality Assurance, and Senior Support Services.
The DHES Director’s Office was, and is, responsible for administering the various programs overseen by the agency, and drafting and enforcing appropriate policies and procedures throughout all organizational units of the agency.
This collection is comprised primarily of subject files, but also includes hearing transcripts, and minimal correspondence. Subject files in this collection cover a vast variety of topics, including but not limited to: health issues and concerns by county, health education, air and water quality issues, disease monitoring and control, information about federal- and state-designated superfund sites, legislative issues, and notices of violation to Montana businesses and individuals.
It should be noted that, intellectually, this collection is primarily comprised of documents from the period prior to the reorganization that split the Department of Health and Environmental Services into Department of Public Health and Human Services and the Department of Environmental Quality. However, the functions represented are almost entirely comprised of those of the Environmental Sciences division, i.e. what would eventually become the DEQ. There are some documents in this collection from POST-DHES/DEQ split (i.e. post-1996).
This collection is arranged by series.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Environmental Quality – Montana; Superfund program (U.S.); Water Quality; Pollution
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence
  - August 1972-April 1973, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 1 / 1-4)
  - Telephone equipment and services for the hearing impaired, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 24 / 1)
  - "Director", 1993 (Box-folder 30 / 1-9)
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1994 September -1996 May (Box-folder 89 / 1-8)
- Hearings
  - (State) Board of Health Hearing, Colstrip 3 and 4, Transcripts Vol. 1-41B (includes Daily Hearing Index and List of Exhibits), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 47/1-15)
  - Anaconda Company, “Application for Change In Regulations” Hearing (Sulfur Dioxide, SO2) (includes transcripts and exhibits), 1971 (Box-folder 50/1-11)
  - Blue Ridge Mining, Petition for Modification of Quality of Ambient Waters (includes Hearing Transcripts, Public Comments, Exhibits, and Testimony), 1991 (Box-folder 51/1-9)
  - Amendment of Rules re: to Particulate matters And Fluoride emissions, 1974 (Box-folder 53/1)
  - Anaconda Aluminum Company, “Application for Variance from Regulations relating to Fluoride And Particulate Emissions” (Depositions: Bolstad, Vichorek, Wake, and Anderson), 1974 (Box-folder 53/2)
  - Anaconda Aluminum Company, “Application for Variance from Regulations relating to Fluoride And Particulate Emissions” (Depositions: Haddow, Holtz, Rapaldi), 1974 (Box-folder 53/3)
  - Anaconda Aluminum Company, “Application for Variance at Casting Facilities at the Columbia Falls Reduction Works”, 1974 (Box-folder 53/4)
  - Anaconda Metallurgical Company, “Application For Variance from SO2 Emission Regulation at Copper Smelter at Anaconda, 1974 (Box-folder 53/5)
  - Billings, State Implementation Plan for Air Quality Maintenance Area, 1978 (Box-folder 53/6)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange vs. State of Montana (Deposition: Roach), 1980 (Box-folder 53/7)
  - Livingston, Amended Request for Hearing, 1974 (Box-folder 53/8)
  - Missoula General Hospital, Certificate of Need (re: construction of nursing home), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 53/9)
  - Montana-Dakota Utilities, Variance from Emissions Rules, 1974 (Box-folder 53/10)
  - North Blaine Estates Subdivision, Denial of Approval, 1982 (Box-folder 53/11)
  - SIP Revision, 1974 (Box-folder 53/12)
  - “Public Hearing on Proposed Regs. To Prevent, Abate, or Control Air Pollution”, 1968 (Box-folder 55/1)
  - Public Hearing…for the Purpose of Revising or Adding to Existing Air Pollution Control Regs., 1970 (Box-folder 55/2)
  - In-situ Mining of Uranium Rule, 1978 (Box-folder 57/1)
  - (Darwin) Johnson Construction (Johnson and McCauley Depositions), 1986 (Box-folder 57/2)
  - Jordan Landfill, 1985 (Box-folder 57/3)
  - Kaiser Cement, Air Quality Permit, 1986 (Box-folder 57/4)
  - Kaiser Cement, “Discharge into Prickly Pear Creek”, 1974 (Box-folder 57/5)
  - Kaiser Cement, Notice of Violation and Order to Appear, 1974 (Box-folder 57/6)
  - Kalispell Regional Linear Accelerator, 1985 (Box-folder 57/7)
  - Kokanee Bend Subdivision, 1982 (Box-folder 57/8)
  - Konitz Contracting (Washington Construction), 1982 (Box-folder 57/9)
  - Kootenai Falls, 1981 (Box-folder 57/10)
  - Lainy’s Lakeview Trailer Court (McAllister), 1980 (Box-folder 57/11)
  - Lewis and Clark County, Air Pollution Control Program/Rules, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 57/12)
  - Lincoln Hill Subdivision (Missoula County), 1985 (Box-folder 57/13)
  - Loma, Solid Waste Management variance (includes Loma landfill), 1985 (Box-folder 57/14)
  - Major Facility Siting Act (MFSA), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 57/15)
  - Meadow Hills Subdivision, 1983 (Box-folder 57/16)
  - (Ivan) Miller Subdivision, 1986 (Box-folder 57/17)
  - Milltown Dam, 1986 (Box-folder 57/18)
  - Montana Pollutant Discharge Elimination System, (MPDES) Milltown Dam, 1988 (Box-folder 57/19)
  - MPDES, Missoula, 1988 (Box-folder 57/20)
  - “Mister ‘M’ Disposal”, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 57/21)
  - Montana Environmental Policy Act (MEPA), Procedures for Compliance, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 57/22)
  - Montana Power Company, Tax Certification, 1984 (Box-folder 57/23)
  - North Blaine Estates, 1982 (Box-folder 57/24)
  - Northwestern Lumber and Cedar, 1984 (Box-folder 57/25)
  - Omnibus Budget and Reconciliation Act, 1988 (Box-folder 57/26)
  - Organ Procurement Rule, 1987 (Box-folder 57/27)
  - Plevna, Solid Waste Management variance, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 57/28)
  - Plum Creek (includes scrapbook), 1987 (Box-folder 57/29)
  - Prairie Subdivision, 1983 (Box-folder 57/30)
  - Radiation Control Rule, 1980 (Box-folder 57/31)
  - Rocky Mountain Phosphates, 1980 (Box-folder 57/32)
  - NPRC, Request for Postponement (re: Decision of Non-degradation), 1992 (Box-folder 58/1)
  - (Albert) Rose (Rose and Earl Eastman Depositions), 1982 (Box-folder 58/2)
  - Royal Village, Water System, 1986 (Box-folder 58/3)
  - Septic Tanks, Cesspools, 1984 (Box-folder 58/4)
  - Septic Tank Cleaner Licensure Rule, 1983 (Box-folder 58/5)
  - Severson Landfill, 1986 (Box-folder 58/6)
  - Shelter Bay Estates (Polson), 1985 (Box-folder 58/7)
  - Sheppard Remainder, 1986 (Box-folder 58/8)
  - Sidney Auto Wrecking, 1984 (Box-folder 58/9)
  - Solid Waste Management Rules, 1981 (Box-folder 58/10)
  - Stone Container Corp., Champion International Frenchtown Mill (MPDES Permit, Discharge Permit, EIS), 1983, 1986 (Box-folder 58/11-13)
  - Subdivision, Fees and Reviews, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 58/14)
  - Transbas Company (Billings) (Disposal of chemicals, 1983 (Box-folder 58/15)
  - Twin Silo Ranchettes, 1983 (Box-folder 58/16)
  - Underground Storage Tanks, 1986 (Box-folder 58/17)
  - Stone Container Corp., MPDES Permit (Missoula mill), 1986 (Box-folder 58/18)
  - United Minerals Variance, 1983 (Box-folder 58/19)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, Creosote spill (Dell) (Transcripts, Documents, Exhibits), 1984 (Box-folder 58/20-23)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, Tie-treating Plant Risk Assessment (Laramie, WY), 1984 (Box-folder 58/24)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, variance (re: burning ties), 1986 (Box-folder 58/25)
  - Valley Vista/ Linda Vista, Village Water and Sewer, 1988 (Box-folder 59/1)
  - Viking Mining, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 59/2)
  - Water Quality, Continuing Education for Water and Wastewater Treatment Operators, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 59/3)
  - Water Quality, Drinking Water Rule, 1987 (Box-folder 59/4)
  - Water Quality, Groundwater Classification Standards and permit program, 1982 (Box-folder 59/5-6)
  - Water Quality, Groundwater Degradation Rule, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 59/7)
  - Water Quality, MPDES, 1982, 1987 (Box-folder 59/8)
  - Water Quality, Non-degradation Water Rules, 1982 (Box-folder 59/9)
  - Water Quality, Phosphorous Cleaners, 1986 (Box-folder 59/10)
  - Water Quality, Public Water/Wastewater/Sewer Systems, 1981, 1985 (Box-folder 59/11)
  - Water Quality, Rule, 1984, 1988 (Box-folder 59/12)
  - Water Quality, Surface Water Rules, 1982 (Box-folder 59/13)
  - Water Quality, Water Quality Report, 1985 (Box-folder 59/14)
  - Water Quality, Water Quality Standards Comments, 1980 (Box-folder 59/15)
  - RE: Streams in Flathead County, 1988 (Box-folder 61/1)
  - Air Quality Permit Rule, 1984 (Box-folder 65/1)
  - Amendment of Rules, re: New Source Performance Standards and Emissions Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants, 1982 (Box-folder 65/2)
  - Amendment of Rules, re: Processing and Public Notice Requirements for MPDES Permits, Public Review Of Air Quality Permit Apps., 1980 (Box-folder 65/3)
  - Fluoride Particles from Aluminum Plants, 1982 (Box-folder 65/4)
  - Lab Licensing, Anaconda variance, Discussion of MAAQS, 1980 (Box-folder 65/5)
  - Proposed Ambient Air Quality Standards, 1981 (Box-folder 65/6)
  - Repeal of Rule ARM, Ambient Air Quality Standards and Adoption of New Rules, 1980 (Box-folder 65/7)
  - Missoula County Air Pollution Control (APC) Program, 1981 (Box-folder 65/8)
  - Amendment of Rules, re: Model Rules of the AG/ Repeal of Rules re: Notice Procedures for Clean Air Rules, 1982 (Box-folder 66/1)
  - Amendment/Adoption of Rules, re: Sulfur Dioxide, 1981 (Box-folder 66/2)
  - “Great Falls (Carbon Monoxide) State Implementation Plan (SIP) Revision”, 1984 (Box-folder 66/3)
  - Billings SO2 Discussion and Update, 1986 July-November (Box-folder 66/4)
  - Butte SIP Revision, 1983 (Box-folder 66/5)
  - Great Falls (Carbon Monoxide) Plan (modification), 1986 (Box-folder 66/6)
  - Prevention of Significant Deterioration (PSD) Rule, Adoption and Amendments (includes Transcripts and Exhibits), 1979-1983 (Box-folder 66/7-9)
  - Re: Regulations to Restrict the Emissions of Sulfur Dioxide (includes Transcripts and Exhibits), 1969 (Box-folder 66/10)
  - SIP, Billings Transportation Plan, 1981 (Box-folder 66/11)
  - SO2 Hearing (includes Transcripts and Exhibits), 1987 (Box-folder 66/12-17)
  - SO2 Rule, Billings, 1987 (Box-folder 66/18-19)
  - Anaconda Company, Renewal of Variance, 1980 (Box-folder 67/1)
  - Anaconda Wire and Cable Company (Columbia Falls), Variance, 1970 (Box-folder 67/2)
  - Stack Heights Rule, 1983 (Box-folder 67/3)
  - Open Burning of Railroad Ties (includes trans.), 1990 (Box-folder 70/1)
  - Blue Range Mining Company, Mining and Mill project (Lewistown), 1991 (Box-folder 71/1)
  - Board of Environmental Review (BER), Amendments to ARM, 1996 (Box-folder 74/1)
  - Columbia Falls PM-10 – Non-Attainment Area Re-designation Hearing (trans.), 1997 June (Box-folder 75/1)
  - Crown Butte Mining, Petition on Temporary Water Quality Standards (Transcript, Vol. I-II), 1995 (Box-folder 76/1-2)
  - Air Pollution Control in Billings and Missoula, 1969 (Box-folder 82/1)
  - Ambient Air Quality Standards, 1967 (Box-folder 82/2)
  - Anaconda Wire and Cable Company (Columbia Falls), Variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/3)
  - Cyprus Mine Corporation (Three Forks), Variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/4)
  - Ideal Cement Company (Trident), Variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/5)
  - Pfizer, Inc. (Dillon), Variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/6)
  - Hoerner-Waldorf Corporation (Missoula), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/7)
  - Humble Oil and Refining Company (Billings), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 82/8)
  - Air Pollution Control Program, Proposed Amendments To the Missoula City-County program, undated (Box-folder 83/1)
  - Amendments and Adoptions re: Air Quality, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 83/2)
  - ARCO, re: Sulfur Oxide Variance for East Helena Lead Smelter and Zinc Fuming Plant (depositions), 1974 (Box-folder 83/3)
  - Anaconda Company, Variance, Compliance, Declaratory Ruling, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 83/4)
  - Barry O’Leary (Billings), variance, 1971 (Box-folder 83/5)
  - Big West Oil Company, variance, 1973 (Box-folder 83/6)
  - Cascade County, re: Local Air Pollution Control programs, 1971 (Box-folder 83/7)
  - Del Conner Lumber, Wood Waste Burner variance, 1973 (Box-folder 83/8)
  - Dupuis Brothers Lumber Company (Polson), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 83/9)
  - Empire Sand and Gravel (Billings), variance (re: Sulfur in fuel), 1971 (Box-folder 83/10)
  - Farmer’s Union GTA (Glendive), variance re: particulate emissions, 1971 (Box-folder 83/11)
  - Farmer’s Union Central Exchange (Laurel), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 83/12)
  - Great Western Sugar Company (Billings), variance (Sulfur in fuels, particulate emissions), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 83/13)
  - Hoerner-Waldorf Corporation, variances, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 83/14)
  - Ideal Cement Company (Trident), variance extension, 1972 (Box-folder 83/15)
  - McIntyre Construction Company/McIntyre Construction Co. and S. Birch, variance, 1971 (Box-folder 83/16)
  - Phillips Petroleum Company, variance re: storage of Petroleum products, 1973 (Box-folder 83/17)
  - Richardson Construction Company (Miles City), air Pollution Variance, 1971 (Box-folder 83/18)
  - Stauffer Chemical Company (Butte), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 83/19)
  - Thompson Falls Lumber Company (Thompson Falls), variance, 1970 (Box-folder 83/20)
  - W.R. Grace and Company/W.R. Grace, Zonolite Div., variance, 1972 (Box-folder 83/21)
  - Re: Disapproval of Certificate of Need for Construction Of Long-Term Care Beds at Clark Fork Valley Hospital (Plains), 1978 (Box-folder 83/22)
  - Public Hearing re: Restricting Sulfur Dioxide Emissions In Montana, 1969 (Box-folder 83/23)
  - Asbestos Rule Amendment Hearing, 1995 (Box-folder 84/1)
  - BHES, Billings/Laurel SO2 Hearing, 1994 (Box-folder 84/2-11)
  - ASARCO, Variance (particulates, visible emissions), 1971 (Box-folder 86/1)
  - ASARCO, Sulfur Oxide, 1976 (Box-folder 86/2)
- Subject Files
  - Air Pollution and Industrial Hygiene (APIH), 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - APIH, Anaconda Company, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - APIH, Hoerner-Waldorf, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - APIH, Miles City, 1973 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - APIH, Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Air Quality, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 1/10-11)
  - Alcohol and Drug Dependency Program, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 1/12-13)
  - Allocations, Grants, and Estimates, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Annual Reports, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Budgets and Budget Hearings, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 1/16-18)
  - Cardiac Diagnostic Center, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Central Services Division, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Child Health Services (includes “Crippled Children Hospitalization”), 1965-1976 (Box-folder 1/21-22)
  - Child Nutrition, 1981 (Box-folder 1/23-24)
  - Civil Rights (Ethel Monroe complaint), 1969 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Clean Lakes Classification, S008258010 (EPA), 1980-1982 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Cleft Palate (08-H-000008-26, -26), 1980-1984 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Community Vaccination (08-H-00001-09, -10, -, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 2/3 12))
  - Comprehensive Health Planning Division (includes Advisory Council meetings), 1968-1972 (Box-folder 2/4-9)
  - “Conference on Improving Quality of Environment”, 1968 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Construction Management Assistance, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Consumer Product Safety (CPSC-C-80-1224), 1981 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Consumer Product Safety (CPSC-C-75-0090, CPSC-C-76-0105, CPSC-C-78-0003), 1975-1978 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Environmental Impact Statements, 1972 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Environmental Sciences Division, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Environmental Services, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Executive Office, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Executive Seminar Program, 1972 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - “Feedlots”, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Fluoridation Projects, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 2/20-21)
  - Health Education, Biennial Report Committee, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Home Health Services, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Hospital and Medical Facilities (HMF), 1971 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - House Joint Resolution 18, 1975 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Jail Surveillance Program, 1972 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Knight, A.C., 1973-1976 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Legal, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Senate Joint Resolution 34, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 3/5-9)
  - Local Health Services, 1972 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Material for State Plan, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Mental Health Advisory Council, 1976 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Modification of Birth Certificates, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Montana Council on Alcoholism, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Montana Power Company, 1972 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Mosquito Abatement, 1972 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Nursing Bureau, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Nursing MCH Project, Silver Bow Co., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Personal Health Services Committee, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 3/19-20)
  - Records and Statistics Bureau, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Regulations Revisions, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Safety Management Institute, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Special Projects, Billings, 1971 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Seeley Lake-Ovando-Swan (S.O.S.) Health Center (aka Seeley Lake Medical Center, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 3/25-26)
  - Social Rehab Services, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 3/27)
  - Seniors Advocacy, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 3/28)
  - 24-hour Answering Service, 1974 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Agency Program Reporting System, 1974 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Agreements (Attorney Shenker in Montana v. Anaconda; non-Employees), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4/3-4)
  - Alcohol and Drug/Alcohol Services Division, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 4/5-8)
  - Annual Report, FY 1974 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Applications for Federal Funds, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Areawide Committee, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Budget and Program Planning, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - CETA Unit, 1974 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Child Health Services, “Crippled Children” Hospitalization, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Comprehensive Health Planning, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 4/15-18)
  - Data Maintenance, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Environmental Health Committee, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 4/20-22)
  - “Foundations”, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - Grants, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Environmental Services, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Equal Opportunity, 1974 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Executive Office, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Health Education, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Health Education, Clearinghouse, 1973 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Health Facilities Committee, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 5/6-7)
  - Health Insurance, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Health Planning and Resource Development Act, 1974 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Health Systems Agency, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5/10-11)
  - Hill-Burton Facilities, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Home Health, 1976 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Hospitals and Medical Facilities, 1973 (Box-folder 5/14-15)
  - “Hotel Hearings”, 1973 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Impact Statements, 1973 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Indian Affairs, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Information Unit, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - Legislative, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Licenses and Permits, 1974 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Montana Center for Handicapped Children, 1974 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Montana Power Company, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Nursing Bureau, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/24)
  - Records and Statistics Bureau, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/25)
  - “Section 1122, Reviews”, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Solid Waste Bureau, 1973 (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Manpower recruitment, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 5/28)
  - Medical malpractice, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5/29)
  - “Miscellaneous”, 1976 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - National Health Service Corps, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Patient Origin Study, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 5/32)
  - “(Office of) Professional Standards Review”, 1976 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Rural Health, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Proposals (approved), 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - “Shared Services”, 1974 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - “Space” (building leases, space allocation), 1973 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - State Summaries, County Health Rankings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Ed., 1971-1976 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Air Pollution Control, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 6/8-11)
  - Air Pollution Control, Contracts, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 6/12-13)
  - Air Pollution Control, Grants, 1982 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Air Pollution Control, Indian Assistance Project, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Air Pollution Control, Study Maps, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Air Quality, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Air Quality: BLM Sites, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Air Quality: Colstrip, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Air Quality: Variances, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Biological Benthic Study, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Bison Engineering, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Board of Health, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 6/23-24)
  - Board of Health: Hearings (hotels, nurses), 1968 September (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Board of Health: Hearings (Buhl Rest Home) (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Board of Health, Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7/2-3)
  - Child Nutrition Program, FY 1982-1984 (Box-folder 7/4-6)
  - Hospital Delivery Room policies, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Indian Health, Survey, 1965 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Laws, Health (RCM), 1967-1974 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Legislative activities, materials, 1964, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7/10-11)
  - Long-term Care Facilities, Policies and Regs., undated (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Miscellany, 1974 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Board of Health, Meetings, May 1966-September 1967 (Box-folder 7/14-22)
  - Board of Health, Meetings, October 1959-March 1966 (Box-folder 8)